<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<metadata><Esri><CreaDate>20130429</CreaDate><CreaTime>07412600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce></Esri><idinfo><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NREL</cntorg><cntper>Donna Heimiller</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>15013 Denver West Parkway</address><city>Golden</city><state>CO</state><postal>80401</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr></cntinfo></ptcontac><descript><abstract>The project estimated the naturally available and technically recoverable U.S. wave energy resources, using a 51-month Wavewatch III hindcast database developed especially for this study by National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration's (NOAA's) National Centers for Environmental Prediction. For total resource estimation, wave power density in terms of kilowatts per meter is aggregated across a unit diameter circle. This approach is fully consistent with accepted global practice and includes the resource made available by the lateral transfer of wave energy along wave crests, which enables densities within a few kilometers of a linear array, even for fixed terminator devices.</abstract></descript><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>None planned</update></status><keywords><theme><themekey>Wave Power Density</themekey></theme></keywords><useconst>This GIS data was developed by the National Renewable Energy Laboratory ("NREL"), which is operated by the Alliance for Sustainable Energy, LLC for the U.S. Department of Energy ("DOE").  The user is granted the right, without any fee or cost, to use, copy, modify, alter, enhance and distribute this data for any purpose whatsoever, provided that this entire notice appears in all copies of the data.  Further, the user of this data agrees to credit NREL in any publications or software that incorporate or use the data.    Access to and use of the GIS data shall further impose the following obligations on the User.  The names DOE/NREL may not be used in any advertising or publicity to endorse or promote any product or commercial entity using or incorporating the GIS data unless specific written authorization is obtained from DOE/NREL.  The User also understands that DOE/NREL shall not be obligated to provide updates, support, consulting, training or assistance of any kind whatsoever with regard to the use of the GIS data.  THE GIS DATA IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL DOE/NREL BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO CLAIMS ASSOCIATED WITH THE LOSS OF DATA OR PROFITS, WHICH MAY RESULT FROM AN ACTION IN CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS CLAIM THAT ARISES OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE ACCESS OR USE OF THE GIS DATA.  The User acknowledges that access to the GIS data is subject to U.S. Export laws and regulations and any use or transfer of the GIS data must be authorized under those regulations.  The User shall not use, distribute, transfer, or transmit GIS data or any products incorporating the GIS data except in compliance with U.S. export regulations.  If requested by DOE/NREL, the User agrees to sign written assurances and other export-related documentation as may be required to comply with U.S. export regulations.</useconst><crossref><citeinfo><title>Wave Power Density</title></citeinfo></crossref><citation><citeinfo><title>Wave Power Density</title></citeinfo></citation></idinfo><metainfo><metextns><onlink>http://en.openei.org/datasets/files/868/pub/wave_power_density.zip</onlink></metextns></metainfo><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>wef</enttypl><enttypd>Wave Power Density (this was originally Wave Energy Flux, but the description was changed part way through the project)</enttypd></enttyp></detailed><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>units</enttypl><enttypd>kW/m as the calculated kilowatts per meter of wave crest width at any given water depth</enttypd></enttyp></detailed></eainfo></metadata>